<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_us"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_us" /><updated>2021-10-16T11:49:55+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Domain | Play Store tutorials and tops of apps</title><author><name>Adrian</name></author><entry><title type="html">Google Play Store Update - how to do it?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/update-play-store/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Play Store Update - how to do it?" /><published>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/update-play-store</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/update-play-store/">&lt;p&gt;Generally, the Google Play Store app is set to update itself automatically when new versions of the application are released. However, depending on the settings and the Internet connection type (via 3G/4G or Wi-Fi), sometimes updating can be done only manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to update Google Play: by using the Google Play Store app or by downloading the APK Magazin Play (an installable app) and reinstalling it separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-play-update---the-recommended-way&quot;&gt;Google Play Update - the recommended way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to upgrade is directly from the application, from the Settings menu – assuming that Google Play can be accessed. Of course, you also need an Internet connection, preferably via Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Google Play and tap the Options button - the three vertical lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the About section, you can see which is the current version of the application. To initiate the update, you have to tap the option Play Store Version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search for the latest Google Play version, and if there is one, an info message will appear, and you will have to press the Install button. If the Google Play Store on your phone/tablet has already been updated to the latest version, then a message like the one below will appear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Google Play cannot be accessed, for e.g., because the Android system was updated to the latest version, and the current version of Google Play has some technical issues, then you have to restart the phone or tablet and redo the instructions. If the problem persists, then the application should be updated as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-google-play-by-reinstalling-the-application-manually---an-alternative-way&quot;&gt;Update Google Play by reinstalling the application manually - an alternative way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In cases Google Play cannot be accessed, showing errors or displaying the main menu, you can install a newer Google Play version, by downloading the application from an external source and reinstalling it on the Android system. It is even possible to install a specific version of Google Play, and not only the latest one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check all the steps you have to follow to update the Google Play app: download and install Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updating Google Play Store is optional. Android and installed apps can smoothly run without updates. However, there are situations when you cannot install apps or games without installing the latest version, or you cannot download digital content. In these cases, the update operation must be done manually, according to the two ways presented above.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>adrian</name></author><category term="Play Store" /><summary type="html">Generally, the Google Play Store app is set to update itself automatically when new versions of the application are released. However, depending on the settings and the Internet connection type (via 3G/4G or Wi-Fi), sometimes updating can be done only manually.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/play-store.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/play-store.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Downloading and installing/updating Google Play | Tutorial</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/download-play-store/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Downloading and installing/updating Google Play | Tutorial" /><published>2021-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/download-play-store</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/download-play-store/">&lt;p&gt;The Google Play app is a center where to customize Android devices, being a default app on most phones or tablets. With this app, you can access, download, install, update and/or use varied content types, for e.g., applications, games, music, movies or TV shows, e-Books, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Android was rooted or if the Google Play Store app is not installed (for many Meizu phones or tablets, for e.g.), you can download, install or update it manually. Learn from this article what is the Google Play Store, where you can download it from and how to install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-google-play&quot;&gt;What is Google Play?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Play is an application developed by Google that allows users to download and install different types of applications, including games, and to access multimedia content from Android devices (the most popular operating system for portable devices - smartphones, tablets, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app or digital content developers can share their products on Google Play, both for free and for a fee, and users of Android devices will be able to access the desired multimedia content or to install apps, games, and so on. In February 2017 there was available a collection of 2.7 million Android Apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Play combines multiple applications, like Google Play Books, Google Play Games, Google Play Movies &amp;amp; TV, Google Play Music, and Google Play Newsstand - all these being independent applications since before 2012 when the current version of Google Play was launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application can have several different names, depending on the Android version, but also on the default system language, for e.g., Google Play Store, Google Store, Play Store, and so forth. And it is a part of the apps suit offered by Google through various Google Play services, which are running on Android by default.
Downloading, installing, updating or accessing Google Play content, can only be done if you have an existing Google Account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-download-and-install-google-play-magazin-play&quot;&gt;How to download and install Google Play (Magazin Play)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the way how to manually install or update the Google Play store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Enable the installation option of apps from unknown sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a security measure, Android’s standard default settings do not allow the installation of third-party apps or games, being downloaded from unknown or unauthorized sources by Google. This setting can be changed, allowing to install apps that do not exist on Google Play, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable the option, follow the instructions:
Go to Settings → Security.
Check the Unknown Sources box.
Confirm this operation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Download Google Play Store (Magazin Play)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At apkmirror.com, there is a big collection of Android apps which can be installed manually instead of using Google Play, and this includes the Google Play app itself, however, named Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Google Play Store download page is here. All you have to do is download the latest version of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is not any compatible version for your device, then you can install the Google Play services (here), which also include Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Install Google Play Store&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install the application, go to the download folder, Downloads, on your Android device.
Open the file containing the Google Play Store app - it has the .apk extension.
The installation window will appear. Press the Install button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait for the process to end, then close the window by pressing the Done button, or immediately open Google Play by pressing the Open button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, you can access the application from the main app screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have accessed the Google Play app, Google Play services will subsequently be installed as well, if there is an Internet connection and if settings allow it, as well. In other words, installing Google Play can also be a solution to both install Google Play Services and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>adrian</name></author><category term="Play Store" /><summary type="html">The Google Play app is a center where to customize Android devices, being a default app on most phones or tablets. With this app, you can access, download, install, update and/or use varied content types, for e.g., applications, games, music, movies or TV shows, e-Books, etc.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/play-store.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/play-store.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Google Play, where to find it and how to use it</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-play-store/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Google Play, where to find it and how to use it" /><published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google-play-store</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-play-store/">&lt;p&gt;Google Play is, in many ways, the most important Android app. The user can utilize it to install a vast collection of Android apps. The user can also access and/or download various digital content such as music, movies, books, electronic magazines, etc., both for a fee and free of charge, depending on the license type under which the content is offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn from this article everything you need to know about Google Play: where to find the application, where to download it from, and how to install the application if it does not exist on your phone or tablet, how to use it and how to solve issues regarding accessing or downloading content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The application has several names, depending on the device manufacturer, the system language, and the Android version, but all of them refer to the same application. If the system language is Romanian, the usual names are Magazin Play, Magazin Google Play, and Google Play Magazin while in English are used names such as Google Play, Play Store, and Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-to-find-the-google-play-app&quot;&gt;Where to find the Google Play app&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application is preinstalled on most Android phones and tablets, but also on Chromebooks, apart from some devices where the manufacturer offers a similar application to Google Play (for the most part, the available content will be different from what Google offers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, the phones and tablets developed by Asian producers (Meizu, Xiaomi, etc.), provide a separate application from the Google Play for users in the region. In this case, Google Play will not be installed on the device by default and, in some cases, it will not be even possible to install the application manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, a shortcut to Google Play Store is located on the main screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case Google Play does not appear on the main screen, the user has to search it on the screen where all the apps are installed. For a faster identification, search the application by using the Google Play’s logo - illustrated in the image from the introduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure the Google Play app does not exist on your phone/tablet, you can search for the application by its name. From the Apps screen, go to the Search icon and enter Google Play, or the Play Store. If this exists, it will appear in the search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haven’t you found the Google Play? Here’s what you can do about it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-you-do-when-you-do-not-find-the-google-play-store&quot;&gt;What can you do when you do not find the Google Play Store?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not find the application, the first thing you need to do is to restart the device, then check if this is installed and turned on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;strong&gt;Settings → go to General → Apps → scroll sideways to All&lt;/strong&gt; → search for the Google Play / Google Play Store app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is not any application with this name, then you will have to download and install Google Play Store manually - see below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if the application appears on the list, then you have to make sure that this is enabled. Access the application, and if disabled, activate it by pressing the Enable button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Disable button appears, it means the Play Store is already enabled, and in this case, you can choose to disable and then reactivate the application. Next, restart the device and see if the store appeared in the menu with Android apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download-the-play-store-app-and-installupdate-it-manually&quot;&gt;Download the Play Store app and install/update it manually&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are rare cases when the Play Store app is not installed by default on your phone/ tablet but fortunately, there is an option to install the app manually. The process consists in setting the device to support installing apps from external sources (that does not belong to the manufacturer), downloading the Play Store app in an installable format (apk), and initiating the setting of the app on the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;All these steps are presented in the article: Download and install Play Store&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tutorial&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the application appears to be installed but it cannot be found, manually installing the application will result in updating the Play Store to a newer version or a particular version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-use-google-play&quot;&gt;How to use Google Play&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use the application, you need a Google Account. Once accessed, this allows you to install apps and games, and also to access and download digital content, such as music, movies, books, electronic magazines, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existing content is available either for free or for a fee or a mix of the two and offers the certainty that distribution is legal. Regarding the apps and games for Android, there is also a high level of confidence about content security, which is tested against viruses and malicious actions. This aspect is not valid when downloading them from the Internet, from sources that are not as secure as Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, this app allows the management of applications, games, and digital content, on all the devices connected to a specific Google account. This aspect is useful, especially for the purchased apps and content because this becomes available on any device (phone, tablet, PC) of the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guiding principle is simple: open the Play Store, browse for the desired application, initiate the download operation, confirm the access rights to Android features, and wait for the install process to finish. In the case of digital content, the access to content is possible either by downloading the content directly to the device or by getting the right to access online digital resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-creates-existing-apps-games-and-digital-content-on-google-play-and-why&quot;&gt;Who creates existing apps, games and digital content on Google Play, and why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The well-known Google company, due to the Play Store, mediates the apps and content distribution, between developers/creators, and consumers. Thus, developers/creators display their applications/content to a large number of users in a competitive environment based on performance and utility. And users have quick access to applications and content that have already been tested by other users and provided under legal and safe conditions for the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, the apps and content are provided for making a profit, but sometimes these are offered for free. In addition to direct marketing of applications and content, another way to generate a profit is to offer some features or auxiliary content for a fee, which are distinct from the free and standard ones. Another way is to display advertisements within applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>adrian</name></author><category term="Play Store" /><summary type="html">Google Play is, in many ways, the most important Android app. The user can utilize it to install a vast collection of Android apps. The user can also access and/or download various digital content such as music, movies, books, electronic magazines, etc., both for a fee and free of charge, depending on the license type under which the content is offered.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/play-store.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/play-store.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>